Joel James

joeljames98.github.io• (512) 963 4817 • joel_james98@utexas.edu

BIOGRAPHICAL SKETCH

I was born in Kerala, India and moved here when I was 2 years old. Growing up as an immigrant taught me to appreciate the blessings I enjoy in this country and to share them with those around me. This is why I am currently studying to be a doctor and serve my greater community.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

Bachelor of Science and Arts in Biology with a minor in Religious Studies - 4.0 GPA May 2021

EXPERIENCE

University of Texas Biostats Teaching Assistant: Austin, TX

August 2019

- Present
 - Co-teach a lab that allows the students to use R-Studio to analyze statistical data
 - Co-teach class with a professor on biostatistical informatics and
 - Answer various questions on the content during class

Olive Garden- Server; Austin, TX

April 2018 - September 2018

- Managed up to 3 tables while maintaining professional and customer friendly demeanor
- Exhibited a thorough knowledge of the menu
- Oversaw up to 17 team members to ensure that all relevant jobs are done

INVOLVEMENT

Foundation Community- Volunteer; Austin, TX

January 2019- present

- Take care of children for the parents in underprivileged communities
- Taught children rudimentary skills such as English and arithmetic
- Provide emotional support and counseling for children who came from broken backgrounds

Silverado Hospice-Volunteer; Austin, TX

March 2019- present

- Provide care for elder patients who are sick and dying such as feeding and changing them
- Provide emotional support and engage in various activities to keep patients occupied and comfortable

HONORS

• UT College of Natural Sciences Distinguished Scholar (Top 4% of college)

Fall 2018 – Present

CNS Second Year Excellence Award

Fall 2018 – Present

Interests and Skills

- Sketch Artist
- Guitar Player
- Soccer Enthusiast
- Proficient in R Studio